<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name='jit.ndi.receive~'>

	<digest>Receive video/audio from a network source using the NDI protocol</digest>
	<description>
		NDI® is a protocol developed by NewTek for streaming video/audio over IP. It allows multiple video systems to identify and communicate with one another over IP, and to encode, transmit and receive many streams of high quality, low latency, frame-accurate video and audio in real-time. NDI can operate bi-directionally over a local area network, with many video streams on a shared connection. It's encoding algorithm is resolution and frame-rate independent, supporting 4K and beyond, along with 16 channels and more of floating-point audio. The protocol includes tools that implement video access rights, grouping, bi-directional metadata, IP commands, tally status and PTZ camera control. <br/>
		<br/>
		NDI® is a registered trademark of NewTek, Inc.
	</description>


	<!--METADATA-->

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name='author'>David Butler / The Impersonal Stereo</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>video</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>streaming</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>network</metadata>
	</metadatalist>


	<!--ARGUMENTS-->

	<objarglist>
		<objarg name="hostname" optional="1" type="symbol">
			<description>Sets the host name of the NDI sender to receive from. If not specified then the host will be set to the local machine.</description>
		</objarg>
		
		<objarg name="name" optional="1" type="symbol">
			<description>Sets the unique name of the NDI sender to receive from.</description>
		</objarg>
		
		<objarg name="num_channels" optional="1" type="long">
			<description>Sets the number of audio channels to receive.</description>
		</objarg>
	</objarglist>


	<!--MESSAGES-->

	<methodlist>
	
		<method name='getruntimeurl'>
			<digest>Outputs the URL for the NDI runtime from the dump outlet.</digest>
			<description>Outputs the URL for the NDI runtime download for the current platform from the dump outlet. This is platform specific.</description>
		</method>
		
		<method name='version'>
			<digest>Prints the jit.ndi package version to the Max window.</digest>
			<description>Prints the jit.ndi package version to the Max window.</description>
		</method>

	</methodlist>


	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->

	<attributelist>

		<attribute name='hostname' get='1' set='1' type='symbol' size='1' >
			<digest>Host name of NDI sender to receive from</digest>
			<description>Host name of the NDI sender to receive from. This can be set even if the host does not currently exist or if it is not currently sending.</description>
		</attribute>
	
		<attribute name='name' get='1' set='1' type='symbol' size='1' >
			<digest>Name of NDI sender to receive from</digest>
			<description>Name of the NDI sender to receive from. This can be set even if the host does not currently exist or if it is not currently sending.</description>
		</attribute>
	
		<attribute name='colormode' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>Output matrices color encoding</digest>
			<description>Output matrices color encoding. If set to ARGB then object will internally convert from UVYV as all NDI video is sent using this format.</description>
		</attribute>
		
		<attribute name='low_bandwidth' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>Low bandwidth mode</digest>
			<description>Low bandwidth mode. When enabled NDI will attempt to reduce the bandwidth used at the expense of image quality.</description>
		</attribute>
		
		<attribute name='tally_onpreview' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>Tally preview status</digest>
			<description>The tally status indicating whether this receiver is displaying the source on preview. Will be communicated back over the network to the sender.</description>
		</attribute>
		
		<attribute name='tally_onprogram' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>Tally program status</digest>
			<description>The tally status indicating whether this receiver is displaying the source on program. Will be communicated back over the network to the sender.</description>
		</attribute>

	</attributelist>


	<!--RELATED-->

	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name='jit.ndi.receive~' />
	</seealsolist>


</c74object>
